<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Libraries | The Synthetic Biology Open Language</title>
    <link>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/tag/libraries/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/tag/libraries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Libraries</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/images/logo.svg</url>
      <title>Libraries</title>
      <link>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/tag/libraries/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>fSBOL</title>
      <link>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/fsharp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;fSBOL is made freely available under the MIT license&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>libSBOL</title>
      <link>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/cpp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;libSBOL provides the core C/C++ interfaces and their implementation for the Synthetic Biology Open Language (SBOL). The current version of pySBOL implements SBOL Core Specification 2.2.0. The library provides an API to work with SBOL objects and to validate the correctness of SBOL 2 documents. Version 2.3.0 of the libSBOL library provides an API to construct designs and to read and write SBOL version 2.2.0 XML/RDF files. libSBOL is made freely available under the Apache 2.0 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cite&lt;/b&gt;: B. Bartley, K. Choi, M. Samineni, Z. Zundel, T. Nguyen, C. Myers, and H. Sauro.pySBOL: A Python Package for Genetic Design Automation and Standardization. ACS Synthetic Biology, (2018). doi:10.1021/acssynbio.8b00336.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>libSBOLj</title>
      <link>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;libSBOLj provides the core Java interfaces and their implementation for the Synthetic Biology Open Language (SBOL). The current version of libSBOLj implements SBOL Core Specification 2.3.0. The library provides an API to work with SBOL objects, the functionality to read GenBank, FASTA, and SBOL version 1 and 2 documents as XML/RDF files, to write GenBank, FASTA, and SBOL version 1 and 2 documents, and to validate the correctness of SBOL 2 documents. libSBOLj is made freely available under the Apache 2.0 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cite: &lt;/b&gt; Z. Zhang, T. Nguyen, N. Roehner, G. Misirli, M. Pocock, E. Oberortner, M. Samineni, Z. Zundel, J. Beal, K. Clancy, A. Wipat, C. Myers. libSBOLj 2.0: A Java Library to Support SBOL 2.0. IEEE Life Sciences Letters 1, 34-37 (2016). doi:10.1109/LLS.2016.2546546.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pySBOL</title>
      <link>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;pySBOL provides Python interfaces and their implementation for Synthetic Biology Open Language (SBOL). The current version of pySBOL implements SBOL Core Specification 2.2.0. The library provides an API to work with SBOL objects, the functionality to read GenBank, FASTA, and SBOL version 1 and 2 documents as XML/RDF files, to write GenBank, FASTA, and SBOL version 1 and 2 documents, and to validate the correctness of SBOL 2 documents. This is a Python binding for C/C++ based libSBOL. Currently, pySBOL supports Python version 2.7 and 3.6 only. pySBOL is made freely available under the Apache 2.0 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cite: &lt;/b&gt; B. Bartley, K. Choi, M. Samineni, Z. Zundel, T. Nguyen, C. Myers, and H. Sauro.pySBOL: A Python Package for Genetic Design Automation and Standardization. ACS Synthetic Biology, (2018). doi:10.1021/acssynbio.8b00336.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sboljs</title>
      <link>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://synbiodex.github.io/SbolStandardWebsite/libraries/javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;sboljs provides the core JavaScript interfaces and their implementation for the Synthetic Biology Open Language (SBOL). The current version of sboljs implements SBOL Core Specification 2.3.0. The library provides an API to work with SBOL objects, the functionality to read SBOL version documents as XML/RDF files and to write SBOL version 2 documents. sboljs is made freely available under the BSD 2-clause license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cite: &lt;/b&gt; J. McLaughlin, C. Myers, Z. Zundel, N. Wilkinson, C. Atallah, and A. Wipat.sboljs: Bringing the Synthetic Biology Open Language to the Web Browser. ACS Synthetic Biology, 8 (1), pp 191–193 (2019). doi:10.1021/acssynbio.8b00338.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
